http://www.rta.nsw.gov.au/about/about-this-website/online-privacy-policy.html

Search
News & eventsWhat we doCareersEnvironment & heritageCorporate publicationsAccess to informationAbout this websiteOnline Privacy PolicyRelated websites
Home
About us
About this website
Online Privacy Policy
Online Privacy Policy
On this page
What information do we collect?
How we collect this information
Analytics services
How we use information collected
How we disclose information
Other uses and disclosures
How we use and disclose feedback information
Email subscription forms and services
Secure storage
Access to data
Updates to this Online Privacy Policy
Users of the Site are entitled to expect that any information gathered while using the Site will be treated within the terms of the New South Wales government's privacy responsibilities and obligations. The New South Wales government's privacy practices are regulated by the Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998 (NSW) (PPIPA) and Health Records and Information Privacy Act 2002 (NSW) (HRIPA).This Privacy Statement sets out how Roads and Maritime Services ('we', 'us' and 'our') collects, uses, discloses and stores information collected through your use of the Site, which may include personal information and health information, and how individuals may access and correct personal information that we may hold. We will only collect, use and disclose this information in accordance with PPIPA, HRIPA and any other applicable laws.In addition to this general Online Privacy Policy whenever customers undertake a transaction with us we provide a more specific Privacy Statement in connection with the transaction.
What information do we collect?
When you access the pages on our Site our computers automatically record information that identifies, for each page accessed:the IP (Internet Protocol) address of the device being used, which can sometimes be matched to broad geographic datathe pages accessed, documents downloaded and transactions completed such as keywords searched for onsite or trip plans and other forms completedthe date and time of your visitthe last site and page visited immediately prior to arriving at the Site, including any search terms used at internet search enginesthe address, hostname and top-level domain, for example .com or .au, of your serverthe type of browser and operating system used on the devicethe bandwidth, that is, your internet connection speedif the device supports JavaScript or other specific technologies and their version numberthe number of screen colours displayed on the devicethe time spent on each page of the SitePersonal Information is information about an individual whose identity can be reasonably ascertained so the information we collect may not always be Personal Information.If you use the feedback facilities on the Site you may also choose to provide us with your personal information such as your name, address, phone number and relevant contact details or other information about you. Depending on your complaint, feedback or the service you require, sometimes this information may also include health information. You may choose to provide feedback anonymously or not provide all the information requested. If you use the feedback facilities anonymously or do not provide us with the requested information we may not be able to reply to your feedback.
How we collect this information
We collect the information on our Site by using 'cookies' which are small pieces of text data that a web server can store on and later retrieve from, a computer. They do not personally identify you, but do identify your browser. Cookies can be either 'persistent' or 'session' based. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer, contain an expiration date, and may be used to track your browsing behaviour upon return to the issuing website. Session cookies are short-lived, are used only during a browsing session, and expire when you shut down your browser.We use first and second party persistent cookies (ie issued and retrieved by the www.rms.nsw.gov.au systems or its service providers) to collect information about visitor behaviour and general website statistics. We may also use services, for example, Facebook Pixel and Cadreon, which may place cookies on your browser to provide relevant advertisements and information from us to your browser or app.The cookies on the Site do not read the information on your hard drive. We make no attempt to associate cookies with users' names or identities. Our server cannot find out your name or email address from the cookies used on the site.You can accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings on your browser. Disabling cookies will not affect your ability to use our websites.
Analytics services
We also use analytics services (for example, Google Analytics, Facebook Pixel and Hotjar) to help us analyse and provide reporting on how users use the Site. These analytics services do not collect information which identifies unless you choose to identify yourself by completing a survey or feedback form.
How we use information collected
The information collected on our Site may be used to allow us to provide a faster and richer interaction when you return to the Site in the future.In addition, the information collected during each visit is aggregated with similar logged information and published in reports so we can identify patterns of usage of the Site. This will assist us in improving the Site and the services offered on it.Feedback that we receive from you through the Site will be used according to the What we do with feedback information section further below.Finally, your information may be used to maintain and protect the security of the Site.
How we disclose information
The information provided will be disclosed to our service providers for them to help us analyse how users use the Site. This information does not identify individual users.We capture this information on its own computers and those of its service providers. Access to the raw data is restricted to a limited number of our staff and our service providers for the purpose of website analysis and to report on the success of Roads and Maritime Services in meeting its communication and access objectives. We will not disclose or publish information that identifies individual machines, or potentially identifies sub-groupings of addresses, without your consent or otherwise in accordance with the PPIPA and HRIPA (for example, disclosure may be required by law).
Other uses and disclosures
We may use and disclose more extensive information than stated above in certain circumstances, including:unauthorised attempts to access files which are not published www.rms.gov.au pagesunauthorised tampering or interference with files published on the Siteunauthorised attempts to index the contents of the Site by other websitesattempts to intercept messages of other users of the Sitecommunications that are defamatory, abusive, vilify individuals or groups or which give rise to a suspicion that an offence is being committed, andattempts to otherwise compromise the security of the web server, breach the laws of the State of New South Wales or Commonwealth of Australia, or interfere with the enjoyment of the Site by other users.We reserve the right to make disclosures to relevant authorities where the use of the Site raises a suspicion that an offence is being, or has been, committed. In the event of an investigation, we will provide access to data to any law enforcement agency that may execute a warrant to inspect our logs.
How we use and disclose feedback information
We provide feedback facilities on the Site to allow users to provide input into the future development of the Site and to comment on the provision of transport services and projects in NSW.Personal information and sometimes, health information, are requested to enable follow up by us for more details or for the purpose of providing a reply to your feedback. This information will only be used for the primary purpose for which it was provided. We will not add your email address or name to any mailing list without your consent. We will not disclose your personal information or health information without your consent or as otherwise may be permitted in accordance with the PPIPA and HRIPA (for example, disclosure may be required by law).We may publish aggregated information about feedback on the Site, to the extent that it does not identify or cannot be used to identify individual users.
Email subscription forms and services
In addition to feedback services, we offer email subscription services via forms on this website. Email subscription services are offered on an ‘opt in’ basis. You can opt out at any time by using the ‘unsubscribe’ link in the emails, or by contacting us.When you subscribe to email newsletters, alerts or other update services from us we will use your personal information in order to provide this content to you. We may also use your personal information to tell you about associated services, public information campaigns or web content we think you might be interested in, but only if you have indicated that you would like to receive this information. We will not use it for any other purpose, nor will we disclose it, unless with your consent or in other circumstances where such use or disclosure is permitted under the Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998 or otherwise permitted or required by law.Clicking the 'submit' button on the subscribe form acts as your consent for us to collect the information you have provided. Before you submit this information we will take reasonable steps to inform you of:where applicable, any law that requires the particular information to be collectedwhich fields are mandatory and which are optional.
Secure storage
Information collected is stored in an appropriately secure format and held by us for archival purposes. When the information is no longer required for the purposes for which it was collected it is deleted.
Access to data
If you wish to:ask questions about this Privacy Statementobtain access to or seek correction of your personal information ormake a complaint in relation to your privacyplease contact the Information and Privacy Unit.
Updates to this Online Privacy Policy
Due to the developing nature of privacy principles for online communication, this Online Privacy Policy may be modified or expanded in light of new developments or issues that may arise from time to time. The amended version will be posted to the Site and will operate from the time it is posted.
Related links
Privacy and access to personal information
Share this page:
Facebook Share
Tweet
RoadsLicenceVehicle registrationTollingBicyclesSafety & rulesUsing roadsEnvironmentCOVID-19 updateMaritimeCOVID-19 boating updateMarine Safety Regulation 2016Maritime newsletterLicenceRegistrationMooringsCommercial vesselsSafety & rules (Boating Handbook)Using waterwaysProperty & planningEnvironmental managementFeesMaritime projectsBusiness & IndustryMajor projects industry hubHeavy vehiclesBusesVehicle examiners, certifiers and assessorsDriving instructorsMotor dealersPartners & suppliersRoad occupancy licencesPoint to Point TransportEvent management guidelinesInnovation Network initiativeTow trucksProjectsSafetyRoad safetyWaterway safetyWork Health & SafetyAbout usNews & eventsWhat we doCareersEnvironment & heritageCorporate publicationsAccess to informationAbout this websiteContact us
Close gallery
